- [士兵尖叫] - [戏剧性音乐]
- [枪声] - [士兵尖叫]
[剑呼啸]
我在庇护所看到了马克。
- 梅基死了。- 我知道。
我亲自开枪打死了她。
[Ackerson]你对庇护所事件的描述
已被证明是可疑的。
我知道你们这些混蛋是怎么想的。我曾经是你。
还有其他的事情要做，还有其他的生活方式。
- [Riz 咕哝] - [John] 你别放弃。
起床。
我知道凯瑟琳·哈尔西的位置。
对你来说这不是钱的问题，不是吗？
是关于她对你做了什么。
索伦永远不会抛下你们任何一个人。
[艾克森]你被捕了。
[女]鲁比·安买下了索伦的船员。
[凯斯勒] 当我爸爸回来时，他会保护我们。
他不会回来了！
我想向你介绍一个人。
这是朱莉娅。她将成为你的侍从。
她在哪？
科塔娜，她很安全。
我给你的问题你有进展吗？
我所有的模拟都返回相同的结果，
无论采取任何行动。
所以没什么可做的。
我正在扫描乐队，
我在干扰中听到了一些声音。
[精英怒吼]
[约翰]你听到一条消息。
这种情况还会再次发生。
我要你贴出你的证据
公约的其他活动。
按下按钮，我会找到你。
这个新人，他带领我们护送一支技术团队
执行一些修复任务。
如果您要将 Cobalt 发送到另一个通信阵列，
你最好告诉他们期待圣约的到来。
我无法授权银牌团队
执行战斗行动。
[电脑蜂鸣声]
[火箭呼啸]
- 我们已经准备好战斗了吗？- 是的。
[凯] 任务到底是什么？
圣约即将到来。
[尖叫]
- [门猛然打开] - [险恶的声音]
[风呼啸]
点击七次即可定位。
[微弱的嘎吱声]
米？
[Riz]钴三号，罗密欧，这是银三号，结束了。
[静电噼啪声]
任何钴元素，这就是银三。
我们正在前往您所在位置的途中，如何抄送？
- [静电爆裂声] - [约翰]尝试继电器。
[Riz]维谢格拉德接力赛，这是银三。
- 无线电检查，结束。 - [静电噼啪声]
[Kai] 我们为此获得空中支援？
[Riz]维谢格拉德接力赛，这是银三。
[凯] 大家都在哪里？
- 超过。 - 我们只能靠自己了
舰队司令部不相信星盟人在致远星。
他们只是认为钴不见了。
这是一次搜救任务
但我们需要为这种可能性做好准备
Cobalt 遇到了一些事情。
[是]有什么契约吗？
[约翰]指挥部认为这个星球是不可触及的。
他们没有看到我们所看到的，
他们不知道我们所知道的。
我会告诉你这一点，我们会联系的。
到那时，就只有我们了。
[凯] 这对你来说似乎是正确的？
[有轻微的咕哝声]
[静电噼啪声]
[阴郁的合唱音乐]
[手指敲击]
[关上门]
[脚步声]
[遥远的、回响的叮当声]
[叮当作响的脚步声]
[约翰] 看看你是否能通电。
[Riz] 收到，长官。
[有] 匆匆离开。
没有钴的迹象，也没有缺口痕迹——
[脉冲声]
[静电噼啪声]
[乱码]
[雷鸣般的隆隆声]
[突然沉默]
[凯] 那到底是什么？
[Riz] 我不知道，我从来没有听说过这样的事。
[约翰] 我有，在庇护所。
[沉重的叮当声]
[不断敲门]
[Vannak] 你现在相信他了吗？
[持续稳定的撞击]
[手指敲击]
[手指敲击；远处的敲打]
[静电噼啪声]
[稳定的冲击力；附近静电爆裂声]
[音频失真]
[布里格斯]站住！
告诉你的团队放下武器，士官长。
[有]这是什么？
- 酋长？- 现在。
我什至无法描述你的处境有多糟糕。
[凯]我什至无法描述
你的脸上将会发生什么。
[Vannak] 这些人到底是谁？
我携带来自舰队司令部的优先命令。
- 什么命令？- 带你进来。
[约翰]你妨碍了我的使命，走开。
没有使命。
- 你偷了一只秃鹰。- 什么？
- 伪造飞行计划。- 她在说什么？
你现在甚至没有被授权穿那些套装
更不用说拿枪指着我的脸了。
因此，请退下，否则我们将与您接触。
[Riz] 祝你好运。
[有]组长，我们该怎么办？
[约翰]钴队在哪里？
- 最后的机会。- 约翰。
[约翰]告诉我钴在哪里，否则我就穿过那扇门。
[布里格斯]我给了你命令。
[有] 叫什么？
首席？
[不断敲门]
[布里格斯]啊，退下，别开火！
- 酋长。- 他们在这里。
我可以证明这一点。
[凯叹气]
[凯]不是这样的。
[忧郁的音乐]
我们在一千英尺高的地方，
风在抽打，电缆在呻吟。
那里的温度不可能超过两度。
- 一月，你知道吗？- 是的。
我再也坚持不住了。
我被绑在安全带上，低头看去，
我告诉亚瑟，我说，“我得走了。”
[笑]他要做什么？
你尿在亚瑟叔叔身上了？
我尿在他身上了 他能做什么呢？
好吧，抬起你的下巴，是的。
你到底怎么了？
这狗屎很有趣。
嗯，我以前听说过。
这有什么区别呢？
当我重复我的话时，你应该笑得很开心。
我就是那个老了的人。
我不知道你在抱怨什么。
我没有抱怨。
嗯，我的意思是，你愿意。
它是什么？
你的秘密在我这里很安全。
这是关于那件事吗
你不应该告诉我吗？
你不应该记得。
我不会选择我忘记的东西。
我可能不得不离开。
在哪里？
而且我不能带你一起去。
[忧郁的音乐]
- 我知道。- 我想要，但我不能。
你看到那座桥了吗？
[艾克森]我无法阻止，爸爸。
你知道那座桥是谁建的吗？
这不取决于我。
- 太晚了。- 那座桥是我建的。
我和你的亚瑟叔叔。
完工那天，
我和你妈妈还有你姐姐一起走过它。
她不可能超过3岁。
握住了她的小手。
她不让我去接她。
她想走完全程。
是的。[笑声]
好的。
那么她什么时候来？
你妹妹。
她走了，爸爸。
朱莉娅走了。
妈妈也是。
哦。
- 只有你和我。- 我知道。
我非常清楚这一点。
别以为我不知道这一点。
哦对不起。
[艾克森]没关系。
对不起，我只是，对不起，我有时会感到困惑。
没关系。
并不意味着我不知道什么是真实的。
明天见，好吗？
好的。
- 答应我... - 是的，我保证。
不，答应我，你不会让他们活捉我。
[凯斯]未经许可缺席，
未经授权部署武器系统，
违反、
我的意思是，你管什么叫偷他妈的秃鹰？
先生。
我正在查看 15 起 UCMJ 违规行为，
其中之一涉及指向已上膛的武器
当着军官的面？
我就是这么做的，先生。
先生，我有可靠的信息。
你有一种感觉。你有错觉。
你走出了链条。
不是吗？
是的先生。
立即生效，
白银队被暂停参加战斗行动，
直至另行通知。
凯斯海军上将，我知道——
你什么都不知道，因为知道不是你的工作。
这是我的。
你的工作就是服从命令。
钴在维谢格拉德，长官。
那是什么？
四天前，Cobalt 被部署到 Aktis IV。
不，这是不对的。
我看到了钴的飞行计划。
- [他们是] 酋长。- 我看到了。
他们改变了它！
[忧郁的音乐]
我知道我看到了什么。
John-117 被解除现役，
并将被限制在军营内
直到他通过精神病学评估。
一个什么？
117 将接受神经化学检查——
这是你，还是艾克森？
约翰，停下来。
收起你的西装，解雇。
你甚至试图保护我们吗？
我是你没有面临军事法庭的唯一原因
你对我们撒谎了。
我告诉了你完成任务需要知道的事情。
- 没有任务。- 钴在维谢格拉德。
- 队长，我可以和你谈谈吗？- 这就是 ONI，这一切。
- 这是艾克森。- 来吧，酋长。
- 你认为他为什么在这里？- 我不能听这个。
你觉得你正在去往哪里？
是！
- 你失控了。- 什么？
你的思维不清晰，你的思维飘忽不定。
你从什么时候开始质疑我的判断了？
自从你开始见到死人。
我没有告诉任何人你说你在庇护所看到了玛基。
约翰，我正在努力帮助你。
我想以你的朋友的身份与你交谈。
我不需要朋友，中士，我需要一个斯巴达战士。
你为什么不尝试这样做呢？
125，你没有被解雇！
[忧郁的音乐]
[模糊的喋喋不休]
[男人] 嘿！
[液体咕噜声]
[悬疑音乐]
【人】她是谁？
[莱拉喘息]
[两人都咕哝着]
[刀声]
- [刀子叮当声] - [莱拉咳嗽]
[莱拉气喘吁吁]
- 鸡蛋？- 嘘！
[附近的声音]
你在做什么？
- 你有危险了。- 我理解了。
不是来自鲁比·安。
我说的是你的船员。
[诡异的音乐]
鲁比·安买下了他们。
- 他们摆脱了索伦。- 什么？
- 你是下一个。- 什么？
- 索伦是吗—— - 我不知道。
你必须带凯斯勒走。
【模仿枪声】
- 来吧，伙计，我找到你了。- 没有。
在这个范围内，你在开玩笑吗？
- 来吧，伙计。- 这是士官长。
[Antares] 是的，这是士官长，
分为八个不同的部分。
[凯斯勒]不，不，你错过了。
[安塔瑞斯] 好吧。
[拉埃拉]你在这里做什么？
玩。
我们有好消息。
船修好了。
我们可以离开了。
你说需要几天时间。
是索伦。
- 我们工作了一整夜。- 过来。
- 我们还没有完成。- 凯斯勒。
[凯斯勒叹气]
该走了。
我能来吗？
- 是的。- 不。
大家都去。
我们都是一家人。
你先走吧，我去船上接你。
我们可以等待。
别为难自己，我能应付。
- 卡琳娜。- 没问题。
[心宿二]卡琳娜。
快点。
[紧张的音乐]
[不祥的音乐]
拿走你的东西。
[凯斯勒]关，你可以出来了。
【情感音乐】
[约翰呻吟]
那么，当你们加入 ONI 时，这就是你们的想法吗？
我们和你一样不喜欢这样，酋长。
[约翰]如果你再靠近一点，
我们得谈谈我们的感受。
[警卫]这只是例行的心理评估，长官。
[门嗖地响]
[门牢牢地关上]
[电梯呼呼地响]
- 对不起。- 什么？
[守卫咕哝]
[紧张的音乐]
- [开门声] - [悦耳的音乐]
- 你好。- 嘿，里兹。
他们取消了我们的训练。
我坐在我的铺位上，所以——
[路易斯]所以你决定来这里？
是的。
[食物滋滋作响]
[路易斯]看看我找到了谁。
嘿，和我们一起吃晚饭吧。
约会之夜过去了。
哦，对不起。
不不不，别听他的。
他的约会之夜的想法以他入睡而告终
听卫星广播，我洗碗。
[路易斯]宝贝，你不洗碗，机器洗碗。
必须有人按下按钮，过来。
你知道，我希望你饿了。
吃完饭我可以给你一些治疗，好吗？
噢，我来这里并不是真的为了这个。
一切都好？
嗯，我想我刚刚开始走路，
但事实证明我真的无处可去。
哦，看在上帝的份上，你让我很难过。
现在我们必须喝酒，坐下。
它看起来很漂亮。
谢谢。
路易斯的健康状况如何？
我们喝什么？
你的最爱。
跟我说话。
前几天你说
还有其他的生活方式，其他的事情。
这是正确的。
像什么？
[轻笑]
我们不知道该任务未经授权。
我，里兹，有。
我们在黑暗中。
郑重声明，
酋长只是在做他认为正确的事情。
嗯，这就是我所关心的。
听着，我很感谢你来到这里
为您的 CO 辩护。
如果酋长走出了链条，
需要有纪律，我明白。
但我们不是为了坐以待毙而生的。
这对我们不好。
我们需要参与战斗。
我不会改变我的决定。
我不是要求你这么做。
我们正处于战争之中，长官。
我们仍然是你们拥有的最好的武器。
您是否建议我部署银牌团队
没有它的领导者？
不，先生。
只有我。
暂时，直到约翰被清除为止。
如果他不是呢？
他是酋长。
二十分钟前，
约翰使被指派监视他的士兵失去了行动能力，
并逃离了这个设施。
什么？
[艾克森]他有和你分享他的计划吗？
计划，什么？
- 有什么计划？- 他在哪里？
哦，我不知道。
上次我们谈话时，
我问你是否有顾虑
关于约翰的精神稳定性，你说——
- 那是以前的事了。- 在什么之前？
这种情况已经持续多久了？
- 我不知道。- 自从 Cortana 被删除后，
或者自从约翰与圣约人特工互动以来？
我查看了该文件。
你在暗示什么？
你我都知道他不是他自己。
听着，凯，我，我想和你分享一些东西，
这不是我作为你的上级说的，这是……
有时人们并没有好起来。
他只是需要时间。
有时，我们坚持下去会造成更大的伤害。
我不能留下来看着他。
[艾克森]我知道。
告诉我该怎么做。
[Kwan] 有时需要几周才能到达这里，有时需要几个月。
有些人根本就没有到过这里。
我们带着四艘船离开了马德里加尔。
我们带着一个来了。
你看到了吗？
这是他们在您签订契约之前处理您的地方。
它不是免费的。
没有什么是免费的。
对不起。
对于发生在你身上的事情。
别这样。
大多数人的情况更糟，
有时我认为这是我应得的。
我正在受到惩罚。
- 别这样说话。- 这是真的。
我不应该在这里，这不是我的生活。
我没有尽到对我的人民和我的星球的责任。
你不能为此责怪自己。
我是关哈
我的家人保护马德里加尔
代代相传的世代数不胜数。
而当轮到我的时候...
[警报声]
[莱拉] 蛋？
[喊叫声]
该走了。我们可以融入。
我们现在必须搬家了。
- [无线电噼啪声] - [喊叫声]
[悬疑音乐]
把它脱下来，他们会注意到你的。
[发动机轰鸣]
- 我们躲起来了吗？- 不。
- 我们去哪？- 为了让你爸爸回来。
我们害怕吗？
不，保持靠近。
[悬疑音乐]
[关]低着头。
别看。
[悬疑音乐继续]
[男子] 向前挺身而出。
[男人2]继续前进！
[悬疑音乐继续]
- 我们现在害怕吗？- 系好安全带。
- [船舶发动机爆破] - [悬疑音乐继续]
[沮丧的喊叫]
一切都会好起来的，凯斯。
我们现在就去找你爸爸。
- 告诉过你了。- [悬疑音乐继续]
- [莱拉]哦，不，不。- [悬疑音乐继续]
[Kwan] 不，我们不会成功的！
【拉埃拉】坚持住！
- [船舶发动机爆破] - [悬疑音乐继续]
- 妈妈！- [悬疑音乐继续]
妈妈！
- [莱拉]该死！- [悬疑音乐继续]
- [船舶发动机关闭] - [悬疑音乐继续]
你在干什么？
等我行动，然后带凯斯勒离开这里。
- 使用舱口。- 你呢？
足够值得你们两个
- 在那个交通工具上。- 不。
答应我你会带他上那艘船。
答应我你会保护他。
- [敲门] - [Antares] 莱拉！
- 不，他们会杀了你。- 妈妈？
[轻柔的音乐]
- [安塔瑞斯] 开门吧，莱拉！- [轻柔的音乐继续]
- 一会儿见。- [轻柔的音乐继续]
[敲门]
[Antares] 别让我烧掉这扇门。
她在这里。
聪明的女孩，这可能会变得混乱。
- Laera，对不起，我从来没有—— - 放弃吧，这不是针对个人的。
这是！
- [吹着陆] - [战士咕哝]
[Briggs] 我们在 80 米处找到了 Cobalt Team
从继电器。
他们在树上。
我们观察到该区域的等离子疤痕。
我认为他们没有预见到它的到来。
[凯斯]谢谢你，队长。
[布里格斯]你想如何处理这个问题？
尸体吗，先生？
[凯斯]没有尸体。
- 我会把它列为 MIA。- 先生。
- 我们走吧。- [门关上]
你还好吗，上将？
不。
我明白。
这是一场悲剧。
- 你知道吗... - 请原谅我？
你知道士官长的怀疑是正确的吗
当你派我们的士兵去敌对时——
我讨厌这种暗示。
我想知道你知道什么
我想知道你什么时候知道的。
- 冷静一下啦。- 冷静下来？
圣约就在这个星球上！
这是时间问题。
这一天是不可避免的。
这是数学，上将。
在每一次分析、每一次模拟中——
这不是一个该死的模拟！
对，不是。
但决定下一步该做什么是我的工作。
我们必须向指挥部发出警报。
我向你保证，你的上级已经完全清楚了。
[嘲笑]
我们需要启动冬季应急计划。
立即开始平民疏散！
结束了，上将。我们赢不了这场比赛。
如果您发出疏散警报，
我们将会陷入混乱、恐慌。
几天前，Cobalt Team受到了圣约元素的攻击。
我们只能假设星盟舰队也不甘落后。
有一个计划，
但这需要一些艰难的选择。
我需要知道你和我在一起。
[紧张的音乐]
- 我们不会打架。- 我没这么说。
我们要战斗，但我们不会赢。
[紧张的音乐继续]
- 这是到达。- 我知道。
数百万人的家园——
我们会尽力节省。
- 这是我的家！- 这也是我的家！
别以为这不会让我付出一切。
[紧张的音乐继续]
——但这就是现实，上将。- [紧张的音乐继续]
我们要么面对它，要么死。
[紧张的音乐继续]
重要资产正在运输中
就在我们说话的时候，我们已经离开了这个星球。
把你的东西放在一起。
- 不告诉任何人。- [紧张的音乐继续]
我不会跑。
当我们能赢的时候，你会再战。
[紧张的音乐继续]
凯斯上将，我可以信赖你吗？
-去你妈的吧。- [紧张的音乐继续]
[Laera] 我的丈夫在哪里？
- 他还活着吗？- 安塔瑞斯？
- 现在还不算太晚，安塔瑞斯。- 是啊，就是。
[船舶发动机启动]
继续吧，关。
[紧张的音乐]
[清嗓子]
[守卫]停下来。
[警卫]等等。
我妈妈在哪里？
- [紧张的音乐继续] - [船舶发动机启动]
- 我很快就能见到她吗？- [紧张的音乐继续]
- 说实话。- [紧张的音乐继续]
- 是的。- [紧张的音乐继续]
- 城里最好的。你要？- 不。
- 尝试一下。- 不，谢谢。
[食客们议论纷纷]
你一直有这个问题。
你无法控制。
你的意思是不可控。
我们达成了协议。
你要给我带来信息，而不是关注。
我有信息。
但我想知道你首先要用它做什么。
我们有一个共同的目标，那就是赢得这场战争。
别误会我是朋友。
- 好的。- [食客们叽叽喳喳]
我相信圣约就在这里。
- 在拉面里？- 到达时。
你是认真的。
一队斯巴达人失踪了。
FLEETCOM 假装他们不知道发生了什么事。
你认为圣约是——
我知道这是契约。
我建议你考虑一下你所说的。
这就是我一直在做的一切。
我一直在想。我一直在说。
似乎没有人在听。
- ONI 知道！- 小声点。
[低] ONI 知道。他们正在掩盖它。
他们为什么要那样做？
ONI 会保护自己。
让他们成为你的敌人，
即使你是士官长也没关系
你将不再有用。
当你不再有用时，那——
- 不，你没听， - 你为什么打架，约翰？
- 什么？- 你们打架，为什么？
为了胜利，为了保卫我们的家园。
为了保护人类。
不，你打架是因为我告诉你的。
你是一名军人，就当一名军人。
这就是你要做的。
回到那里吧。
返回舰队司令部。
亲你必须亲的屁股。
你去双桅船里度过你的时光吧。
微笑。
你永远不会再提起它。
他们可能会再给你一枚奖牌。
[椅子刮伤]
[紧张的音乐]
我需要知道我们彼此理解。
上将，您到底什么时候离开 ONI 的？
如果你离开这里，我就帮不了你了。
- 你从未离开过。- 退下，约翰。
我不这么认为。
[紧张的音乐继续]
[艾克森]我从来不明白它们到底有多么脆弱。
脆弱的？
是的，因为你就是这样做的。
不。
当他们还是孩子的时候，你就带走了他们。
你调节了它们。
然后当他们长大到能够独立思考时，
你确保他们永远不会。
你把这些颗粒放进去。
所以他们从来不需要感受到欲望
或野心或偏好。
所以他们永远不会选择除了你以外的任何人。
就是这样，不是吗？
- 你为什么在这？- 我只是来道别。
我走了。
而我，我想我想让你知道
你的努力没有白费，凯瑟琳，
你不会在这里看到它。
但你所创造的这些东西，尽管可能已经破碎，
他们将成为基础
为了一些非凡的事情。
我希望这最终能给你带来一些安慰。
[轻柔的音乐]
你不想知道她是怎么死的吗？
[轻柔的音乐继续]
什么？
朱莉娅. 你以为我不知道她是谁吗？
我记得他们所有人。
尤其是你妹妹。
她……她实在是太好奇了。
她曾经问过很多问题。
但你永远不知道谁会成功
增强和谁不是。
- 她没有。- [轻柔的音乐继续]
- 不。 - [轻柔的音乐继续]
她快要死了。
她不知道为什么。她无法理解。
我或多或少地告诉了她你刚才告诉我的事情。
即使她看不到，
她将是下一步前进的一小部分。
不知道她是否听懂了。
她很害怕。
但我知道她非常爱你。
我希望这能给你一些安慰。
[轻柔的音乐继续]
[轻笑]是的。
[戏剧性的呼气]
我以为你要走了。
我不想让你孤单。
- 我不是怪物。- [轻柔的音乐继续]
[紧张的音乐]
[艾克森]我会让你们两个重新认识一下。
[紧张的音乐继续]
[稳定的金属撞击声]
你让我很难帮助你。
- 老板，我们正在退出滑行空间。- 我听到了。
我让他们为所欲为...
[戏剧性的笑声] ...你已经死了。
我们对你很好，安塔瑞斯。
哦。出色地。
谢谢你让我勉强存在
并通过四种方式勉强维持微薄的生活
当你和你丈夫一起度过的时候，和这些笨蛋在一起
- 所有牧歌的钱-- - 你在说什么？
别装傻了！
我知道你不是。
我通常可以和我丈夫讲道理，
但当他发现这件事时——
我其实并不担心。最后我见到索伦，
他在一艘前往致远星的监狱船上。
所以安顿下来。
可能需要一段时间。
- 你就是个混蛋。- 不，我是一个机会主义者。
[远处金属叮当作响]
现在，它在哪里？
[远处叮当声继续]
有人可以处理一下吗？
我听不到自己的想法。
[远处叮当声继续]
谢谢。
我不知道鲁比·安向你承诺了什么
但你被耍了，安塔瑞斯，现在还不算太晚。
“请停一下。”
索伦告诉你一切。
你知道他把它藏在哪里了。
- 藏了什么？- 宝藏，宝贝，财物。
[莱拉笑]
你觉得这很有趣吗？
因为我向你保证...
[紧张的音乐]
...它不是。
你所说的宝藏是装满了一个盒子
起初并不值钱的氘代币。
- 听够了。- [紧张的音乐继续]
鲁比·安不想要钱。
她想要瓦砾。
- [枪栓] - [莱拉喘气]
- 冷静下来。- [紧张的音乐继续]
你为什么要让我这么做？
你以为我想让凯斯勒成为孤儿吗？
我爱那个孩子。
她在笑你。
[远处叮当声继续]
- 你听到那个声音了吗？- 是的。
是的，你认为你应该为此做点什么？
我在看。
[远处叮当声继续]
去看看是什么发出了这个声音。
- 藏品在哪里？- 她在拖延。
你能闭嘴吗？
我不记得询问过任何人的意见。
我是队长。
这是我的船，
这是你最后的机会，莱拉。
[远处叮当声继续]
- 它在哪里？- [紧张的音乐继续]
我不能告诉你，因为它不存在。
如果它确实存在，我不会告诉你。
[紧张的音乐继续]
你刚刚把它从我手里夺走了。
请记住，我不想要接下来发生的事情。
[紧张的音乐继续]
- [戏剧性音乐] - [莱拉呻吟]
- [门嘟嘟声] - [液压装置发出嘶嘶声]
[紧张的音乐]
你有一分钟​​的时间重新考虑你的立场。
- [倒计时蜂鸣声] - [空气嘶嘶声]
事情不必是这样的。
[莱拉呼吸困难]
想想凯斯勒吧！
索伦在致远星，谁来照顾他？
- [莱拉呼吸困难] - [紧张的音乐建筑]
- 告诉我我想知道什么-- - [血溅]
[警报声]
[急促的喘息]
[轻柔的音乐]
- [刀子在金属上叮当作响] - [轻柔的音乐继续]
凯斯勒在哪里？
- 关？- [轻柔的音乐继续]
关，我问你一个问题——
- [Carina 咕哝] - [Kwan 大喊]
- [刀声响起] - [紧张的音乐继续]
- [Kwan 咕哝] - [身体重击]
[轻柔的音乐]
- 我把他送上了交通工具 - 我告诉过你要和他在一起。
- 我不能。- 为什么不？
因为那样你就死了。
[轻柔的音乐继续]
[敲门]
我需要和佩雷斯下士谈谈。
- 她不在这里。- 她在哪？
她是个好女孩。
是的女士。
但我认为魔鬼会跟着你。
[轻柔的音乐]
现在是几奌？
- 晚的。- 嗯。
[轻柔的音乐继续]
我在这是要干嘛？
你还记得我们聊过什么吗？
你要求我...
为了不让他们活捉我？
是啊，没错。
今天是这一天吗？
今天就是这一天。
感谢上帝。
哦。
[轻柔的音乐继续]
有人来看你，爸爸。
[喘气]
[轻柔的音乐继续]
哦，朱莉娅。
朱莉娅.
[门打开的声音很大]
- [沉重的脚步声] - [佩雷斯静静地祈祷]
佩雷斯下士。
[用西班牙语轻声祈祷]
- [门关上] - [佩雷斯继续祈祷]
你以前从来没有去过教堂，是吗？
嗯-嗯。
人们来到这里是为了寻求安慰。
为了保护。
寻求答案。
他们找到他们了吗？
有时。
你？
在圣所，
在契约到来之前，我...
我在雾中……看到了一些东西。
你是说那个女人吗？
[呼吸困难]
她是真实的，不是吗？
是的。
我不睡觉。
我无法将那个声音从我的脑海中抹去。
这是圣所的录音。
这不仅仅是干扰。
不只是声音。
下面有东西。
【桑赫利演奏录音】
它是什么？
[桑赫利录音播放继续]
一个祈祷者。
我给你们带来祝福，致远星的人们。
【桑赫利演奏录音】
[桑赫利的声音]
[Perez]要知道我是毫不留情地来的。
[佩雷斯]没有怜悯。
[桑赫利的声音]
[佩雷斯]知道我是你灭绝的工具。
[佩雷斯]我将这个星球作为燔祭带来。
[紧张的音乐]
[桑赫利的声音]
[Perez]在这个祭坛上，我放置了恶魔的头颅。
[佩雷斯]愿他的鲜血标志着通往圣环的道路
并奉献我人民的伟大旅程。
[桑赫利的声音]
[佩雷斯]知道我是 Var 'Gatanai。
[佩雷斯]知道我是……死亡。
[紧张的音乐]
他们已经来了...
不是吗？
[紧张的音乐继续]
[大规模爆炸]
[闭幕主题曲]
【签名主题剧】
- [soldiers scream]
- [dramatic music]
- [gun fires]
- [soldier screams]
[sword whooshes]
I saw Makee on Sanctuary.
- Makee's dead.
- I know.
I shot her myself.
[Ackerson] Your account
of events on Sanctuary
has proven dubious.
I know how you assholes think.
I was you once.
There's other things to be,
other ways to live.
- [Riz grunting]
- [John] Don't you quit.
Get up.
I know the location
of Catherine Halsey.
It's not about the money
for you, is it?
It's about what she did to ya.
Soren never would've
left any of you behind.
[Ackerson]
You're under arrest.
[Woman] Ruby Ann
bought Soren's crew.
[Kessler] When my dad comes
back, he'll protect us.
He's not coming back!
I want to introduce
you to someone.
This is Julia.
She'll be your attendant.
Where is she?
Cortana, she's secure.
Have you made any progress
with the problem I gave you?
All of my simulations
returned the same result,
regardless of any action taken.
So there's nothing to be done.
I was scanning the band,
and I heard something
in the interference.
[Elite roars]
[John] You heard a message.
This will happen again.
I want you to post your evidence
of the Covenant's
other activities.
Press the button,
and I'll find you.
This new guy, he's got
us escorting a tech team
on some fix-it mission.
If you're sending Cobalt
to another comms array,
you better tell them
to expect the Covenant.
I cannot authorize Silver Team
to perform combat operations.
[computer beeping]
[rockets whooshing]
- We're cleared for combat?
- Affirmative.
[Kai] What exactly
is the mission?
The Covenant's on Reach.
[screaming]
- [door crashes open]
- [sinister noises]
[wind whistling]
Seven clicks to target.
[faint creaking sound]
Riz?
[Riz] Cobalt Three, Romeo,
this is Silver Three, over.
[static crackling]
Any Cobalt element,
this is Silver Three.
We are en route to your
position, how copy?
- [static crackles]
- [John] Try the relay.
[Riz] Visegrád Relay,
this is Silver Three.
- Radio check, over.
- [static crackling]
[Kai] We getting
air support for this?
[Riz] Visegrád Relay,
this is Silver Three.
[Kai] Where is everybody?
- Over.
- We're on our own.
FLEETCOM doesn't believe
the Covenant's on Reach.
They just think
Cobalt's missing.
This is a search
and rescue mission,
but we need to be prepared
for the possibility
that Cobalt ran into something.
[Vannak] Something Covenant?
[John] Command thinks
this planet's untouchable.
They haven't
seen what we've seen,
and they don't
know what we know.
I'll tell you this,
we will have contact.
Until then, it's just us.
[Kai] This seem right to you?
[Vannak grunts softly]
[static crackling]
[somber choral music]
[finger tapping]
[doors slam]
[footsteps]
[distant, echoing clank]
[clanking footsteps]
[John] See if you
can get the power up.
[Riz] Copy, Chief.
[Vannak] Left in a hurry.
No sign of Cobalt,
no breach marks at the--
[pulse blaring]
[static crackling]
[garbled voices]
[thunderous rumble]
[sudden silence]
[Kai] What the hell was that?
[Riz] I don't know, I've
never heard anything like it.
[John] I have, on Sanctuary.
[heavy clank]
[steady pounding on doors]
[Vannak] You believe him now?
[steady pounding continues]
[finger tapping]
[finger tapping;
distant pounding]
[static crackling]
[steady pounding;
nearby static crackle]
[distorted audio]
[Briggs]
Stand down!
Tell your team to lower
their weapons, Master Chief.
[Vannak] What is this?
- Chief?
- Now.
I can't even describe
the amount of shit you're in.
[Kai] I can't even describe
what's about to
happen to your face.
[Vannak] Who the hell
are these people?
I carry priority
orders from FLEETCOM.
- What orders?
- To bring you in.
[John] You are impeding
my mission, move.
There is no mission.
- You stole a Condor.
- What?
- Falsified a flight plan.
- What is she talking about?
You're not even authorized to
be in those suits right now,
let alone pointing
a gun at my face.
So stand down, or
we will engage you.
[Riz] Good luck with that.
[Vannak] Chief, what do we do?
[John] Where is Cobalt Team?
- Last chance.
- John.
[John] Tell me where Cobalt is,
or I'm going through that door.
[Briggs] I gave you an order.
[Vannak] What's the call?
Chief?
[steady pounding on doors]
[Briggs] Ah, stand
down, do not fire!
- Chief.
- They were here.
I can prove it.
[Kai sighs]
[Kai] Not like this.
[somber music]
We were a thousand feet up,
wind whipping, cables groaning.
Couldn't have been more
than two degrees up there.
- January, you know?
- Yeah.
And I can't hold it anymore.
I'm strapped in the
harness, and I look down,
I tell Arthur,
I say, "I gotta go."
[laughs]
What's he gonna do?
You peed on Uncle Arthur?
I peed on him.
What could he do?
Okay, lift your chin up, yeah.
What the hell's wrong with you?
This shit is funny.
Well, I've heard it before.
What difference does that make?
You're supposed to damn well
laugh when I repeat myself.
I'm the one that's senile.
I don't know what you're
complaining about.
I'm not complaining.
Well, I mean, you want to.
What is it?
Your secret's safe with me.
Is this about that thing
that you weren't
supposed to tell me?
You weren't supposed
to remember.
I don't choose what I forget.
I might have to go away.
Where?
And I can't take you with me.
[somber music]
- I know.
- I want to, but I can't.
You see that bridge?
[Ackerson] I can't stop it, Dad.
You know who built that bridge?
It's not up to me.
- It's too late.
- I built that bridge.
Me and your Uncle Arthur.
The day it was finished,
I walked across it with
your mum, and your sister.
She couldn't have
been more than 3.
Held her little hand.
She wouldn't let me pick her up.
She wanted to walk
the whole way.
Yeah.
[chuckles]
All right.
So when's she coming?
Your sister.
She's gone, Dad.
Julia's gone.
Mum, too.
Oh.
- It's just you and me.
- I know that.
I damn well know that.
Don't think that
I don't know that.
Oh, sorry.
[Ackerson] It's okay.
Sorry, I just, sorry,
I just get confused sometimes.
It's okay.
Doesn't mean that I
don't know what's real.
See you tomorrow, okay?
Okay.
- Promise me...
- Yeah, I promise.
No, promise me you won't
let them take me alive.
[Keyes] Absent without leave,
unauthorized deployment
of weapons systems,
violation of,
I mean, what do you even call
stealing a goddamn Condor?
Sir.
I'm looking at 15
infractions of the UCMJ,
one of which involves
pointing a loaded weapon
in the face of an officer?
I did that, sir.
Sir, I had credible information.
You had a feeling.
You had a delusion.
You went outside the chain.
Didn't ya?
Yes, sir.
Effective immediately,
Silver Team is suspended
from combat operations,
'til further notice.
Admiral Keyes, I know--
You know nothing because
it's not your job to know.
It's mine.
Your job is to follow orders.
Cobalt was at Visegrád, sir.
What's that?
Four days ago, Cobalt
was deployed to Aktis IV.
No, this isn't right.
I saw Cobalt's flight plan.
- [Vannak] Chief.
- I saw it.
They changed it!
[somber music]
I know what I saw.
John-117 is relieved
from active duty,
and will be confined to barracks
'til such a time as he clears
a psychiatric evaluation.
A what?
117 will submit
to neurochemical--
Is this you, or
is this Ackerson?
John, stop.
Rack your suits, dismissed.
Did you even try to defend us?
I'm the only reason you're
not facing a court-martial.
You lied to us.
I told you what you needed to
know to complete the mission.
- There was no mission.
- Cobalt was at Visegrád.
- Chief, can I talk to you?
- This is ONI, all of it.
- This is Ackerson.
- Come on, Chief.
- Why do you think he's here?
- I can't listen to this.
Where do you think you're going?
Vannak!
- You are out of control.
- What?
You're not thinking
straight, you're erratic.
Since when do you
question my judgment?
Since you started
seeing dead people.
I didn't tell anyone you said
you saw Makee on Sanctuary.
John, I'm trying to help you.
I'm trying to talk to you,
as your friend.
I don't need a friend,
Petty Officer, I need a Spartan.
Why don't you try doing that?
125, you are not dismissed!
[somber music]
[indistinct chatter]
[man] Hey!
[liquid burbling]
[suspenseful music]
[Person] Who is she?
[Laera gasps]
[both grunting]
[knife zings]
- [knife clatters]
- [Laera coughing]
[Laera panting]
- Kwan?
- Shh!
[nearby voices]
What're you doing?
- You're in danger.
- I can see that.
Not from Ruby Ann.
I'm talking about your crew.
[eerie music]
Ruby Ann bought them off.
- They got rid of Soren.
- What?
- You're next.
- Is Soren--
- I don't know.
You have to get Kessler and go.
[imitating gunfire]
- Come on, man, I got you.
- Did not.
Are you kidding me,
at this range?
- Come on, man.
- It's Master Chief.
[Antares] Yeah,
it's Master Chief,
in eight different pieces.
[Kessler] Nope, nope,
you missed.
[Antares] Fine.
[Laera]
What are you doing here?
Playing.
We have good news.
Ship's fixed.
We can leave.
You said it would
take a couple of days.
It's Soren.
- We worked all night.
- Come here.
- We're not finished.
- Kessler.
[Kessler sighs]
Time to go.
Can I come?
- Yeah.
- No.
Everybody goes.
We're all family.
You go ahead, I'll
meet you at the ship.
We can wait.
Don't trouble
yourselves, I can manage.
- Carina.
- It's no trouble.
[Antares] Carina.
Come on.
[tense music]
[ominous music]
Get your things.
[Kessler] Kwan,
you can come out.
[emotional music]
[John groans]
So, when you guys joined ONI,
is this what you had in mind?
We don't like this any
more than you do, Chief.
[John] If you get any closer,
we're gonna have to
talk about our feelings.
[Guard] It's just a routine
psych eval, Chief.
[doors swoosh]
[doors close firmly]
[elevator whirring]
- Sorry.
- What?
[guards grunting]
[tense music]
- [door clicks]
- [pleasant music]
- Hi.
- Hey, Riz.
They canceled our training.
I was sitting in my bunk, so--
[Louis] So you decided
to come by here?
Yeah.
[food sizzling]
[Louis] Look who I found.
Hey, join us for dinner.
There goes date night.
Oh, I'm sorry.
No, no, no, no,
don't listen to him.
His idea of date night ends
with him falling asleep
listening to the sat-link,
and me doing the dishes.
[Louis] Babe, you don't do
the dishes, the machine does.
Someone has to press
the button, come here.
You know, I hope you're hungry.
I can give you some
treatment after we eat, yeah?
Oh, I didn't really
come here for that.
Everything okay?
Um, I guess I just
started walking,
but it turns out I don't
really have anywhere to go.
Oh, for God's sake,
you're making me sad.
Now we have to drink, sit.
It looks beautiful.
Thank you.
Louis' health?
What are we drinking?
Your favorite.
Talk to me.
The other day, you said
there were other ways to live,
other things to be.
That's right.
Like what?
[soft chuckle]
We didn't know the
mission wasn't authorized.
Me, Riz, Vannak.
We were in the dark.
And for the record,
Chief was just doing what
he thought was right.
Well, that's what concerns me.
Look, I appreciate
you coming down here
to advocate for your CO.
If the Chief went
outside the chain,
there needs to be
discipline, I get that.
But we're not built
to sit around and wait.
It's not good for us.
We need to be in the fight.
I'm not gonna
change my decision.
I'm not asking you to.
We are at war, sir.
We're still the best
weapons you have.
Are you suggesting
I deploy Silver Team
without its leader?
No, sir.
Just me.
Temporarily,
'til John's cleared.
And if he's not?
He's the Chief.
Twenty minutes ago,
John incapacitated the soldiers
assigned to monitor him,
and escaped this facility.
What?
[Ackerson] Did he share
his plans with you?
Plans, what?
- What plans?
- Where is he?
Oh, I don't know.
Last time we spoke,
I asked you if you had concerns
about John's mental
stability, and you said---
- That was before.
- Before what?
How long has this been going on?
- I don't know.
- Since Cortana was removed,
or since John interacted
with the Covenant agent?
I reviewed the file.
What are you implying?
You and I both know
he's not himself.
Look, Kai, I, I want to
share something with you,
and this isn't me speaking
as your superior, this is...
sometimes people
don't get better.
He just needs time.
Sometimes, we do more
damage by holding on.
I can't stay and watch him.
[Ackerson] I know.
Tell me what to do.
[Kwan] Sometimes it takes weeks
to get here, sometimes months.
Some never get here at all.
We left Madrigal
with four ships.
We arrived with one.
You see that?
That's where they process
you before you're indentured.
It's not free.
Nothing is free.
I'm sorry.
For what
happened to you.
Don't be.
Most people have it worse,
and sometimes I
think I deserve it.
I'm being punished.
- Don't talk like that.
- It's true.
I'm not supposed to be
here, this isn't my life.
I failed my responsibility
to my people and my planet.
You can't blame
yourself for that.
I'm Kwan Ha.
My family protected Madrigal
for more generations
than anyone can count.
And when it was my turn...
[alarm blaring]
[Laera] Kwan?
[voices shouting]
It's time to go.
We can blend in.
We have to move now.
- [radios crackling]
- [voices shouting]
[suspenseful music]
Take it off, they'll notice you.
[engine rumbling]
- Are we hiding?
- No.
- Where are we going?
- To get your dad back.
Are we scared?
No. Stay close.
[suspenseful music]
[Kwan] Keep your head down.
Don't look.
[suspenseful music continues]
[man]
Rising forward.
[man 2]
Keep moving!
[suspenseful music continues]
- Are we scared now?
- Strap in.
[suspenseful music continues]
- [ship engine blasting]
- [suspenseful music continues]
[dismayed shouting]
Everything's gonna be okay, Kes.
We're gonna get your dad now.
- Told you.
- [suspenseful music continues]
- [Laera] Oh, no, no.
[Kwan] No, we're
not gonna make it!
[Laera] Hold on!
- [ship engine blasting]
- [suspenseful music continues]
- Mom!
Mom!
- [Laera] Damn it!
- [suspenseful music continues]
- [ship engine powers down]
What are you doing?
Wait for my move,
then get Kessler out of here.
- Use the hatch.
- What about you?
It's worth enough
to get both of you
- on that transport.
- No.
Promise me you'll
get him on that ship.
Promise me you'll protect him.
- [banging on door]
- [Antares] Laera!
- No, they'll kill you.
- Mom?
[gentle music]
- [Antares] Open up, Laera!
- [gentle music continues]
- I'll see you soon.
[banging on door]
[Antares] Don't make
me torch this door.
There she is.
Smart girl, this
could have got messy.
- Laera, I'm sorry, I never--
- Give it up, it's not personal.
It is!
- [blows landing]
- [fighters grunting]
[Briggs] We found
Cobalt Team 80 meters
from the relay.
They were in the trees.
We observed plasma
scarring in the area.
I don't think they
saw it coming.
[Keyes] Thank you, Captain.
[Briggs] How would you
like to handle this?
The bodies, sir?
[Keyes] There are no bodies.
- I would list it as MIA.
- Sir.
- Let's go.
- [door closes]
You all right, Admiral?
No.
I understand.
It's a tragedy.
- Did you know...
- Pardon me?
Did you know that Master Chief's
suspicions were valid
when you sent our soldiers
out into a hostile--
I resent the implication.
I want to know what you knew,
and I want to know
when you knew it.
- Just calm down.
- Calm down?
The Covenant is on this planet!
It was a matter of time.
This day was inevitable.
It's mathematics, Admiral.
In every analysis,
every simulation--
This is not
a goddamn simulation!
Right, it's not.
But it's my job to
decide what to do next.
We have to alert command.
I assure you, your superiors
are already fully aware.
[scoffs]
We need to initiate
the Winter Contingency.
Begin immediate
civilian evacuation!
It's over, Admiral.
We don't get to win this one.
If you send out
an evacuation alert,
we'll have chaos, panic.
The Covenant element hit
Cobalt Team days ago.
We can only assume the Covenant
fleet isn't far behind.
There is a plan in place,
but it's going to require
some hard choices.
I need to know that
you're with me.
[tense music]
- We're not gonna fight.
- I didn't say that.
We're going to fight, we're
just not going to win.
[tense music continues]
- This is Reach.
- I know.
Home to millions of people--
And we will save what we can.
- This is my home!
- It is my home too!
Don't think for a second this
doesn't cost me everything.
[tense music continues]
- but this is reality, Admiral.
- [tense music continues]
We can either face it or we die.
[tense music continues]
Essential assets are
being transported
off the planet as we speak.
Get your things together.
- Tell no one.
- [tense music continues]
I won't run.
You'll fight another
day when we can win.
[tense music continues]
Admiral Keyes,
can I count on you?
[tense music continues]
- Go fuck yourself.
- [tense music continues]
[Laera] Where's my husband?
- Is he alive?
- Antares?
- It's not too late, Antares.
- Yeah, it is.
[ship engines power up]
Go on, Kwan.
[tense music]
[voice clears throat]
[guard]
Halt.
Wait.
Where's my mom?
- [tense music continues]
- [ship engine powers up]
- Will I see her soon?
- [tense music continues]
- Tell the truth.
- Yes.
- [tense music continues]
- Best in the city. You want?
- No.
- Try it.
- No, thank you.
[diners chatter]
You've always had this problem.
You are not in control.
You mean not controllable.
We had an agreement.
You were to bring me
information, not attention.
I have information.
But I wanna know what you're
gonna do with it first.
We have a common
goal to win the war.
Don't mistake me for a friend.
- Okay.
- [diners chatter]
I believe the Covenant is here.
- In the ramen?
- On Reach.
You're serious.
A team of Spartans went missing.
FLEETCOM is pretending they
don't know what happened.
And do you think it's
the Covenant that--
I know it's the Covenant.
I suggest you consider
what you're saying.
That's all I've been doing.
I've been thinking it.
I've been saying it.
And nobody seems
to be listening.
- ONI knows!
- Keep your voice down.
[low] ONI knows.
They're covering it up.
Why would they do that?
The ONI protects itself.
Make them your enemy,
and it won't matter that
you're Master Chief,
you will cease to be useful.
And when you cease
to be useful, that--
- No, you're not listening,
- Why do you fight, John?
- What?
- You fight, why?
To win, to defend our home.
To preserve humanity.
No, you fight
because I tell you to.
You are a soldier, be a soldier.
This is what you will do.
Go back there.
Go back to FLEETCOM.
Kiss whatever ass
you have to kiss.
You go do your time in the brig.
Smile.
You'll never speak of it again.
They will probably
give you another medal.
[chair scrapes]
[tense music]
I need to know we
understand each other.
When exactly did you
leave ONI, Admiral?
If you walk out of here,
I won't be able to help you.
- You never left.
- Stand down, John.
I don't think so.
[tense music continues]
[Ackerson] I never understood
how fragile they really are.
Fragile?
Yes, because you
made them that way.
No.
You took them when
they were children.
You conditioned them.
And then when they were old
enough to think for themselves,
you made sure they never would.
You put in those pellets.
So they never had to feel desire
or ambition or preference.
So they would never choose
anyone other than you.
And that's it, isn't it?
- Why are you here?
- I just came to say goodbye.
I'm leaving.
And I, I suppose
I wanted you to know
that your efforts weren't
in vain, Catherine,
you won't be here to see it.
But these things that you
made, broken as they may be,
they're going to
become the foundation
for something extraordinary.
And I hope that gives you
some comfort in the end.
[gentle music]
Don't you want to
know how she died?
[gentle music continues]
What?
Julia. Did you think I didn't
know who she was?
I remember all of them.
Especially your sister.
She was... she was so curious.
She used to ask
so many questions.
But you never know
who's going to make it through
the augmentation and who isn't.
- And she didn't.
- [gentle music continues]
- No.
She was dying.
She didn't know why.
She couldn't understand.
I told her more or less
what you just told me.
That even though
she wouldn't see it,
she would be this small part
of the next step forward.
I don't know if she understood.
She was so scared.
But I do know that she
loved you very much.
And I hope that gives
you some comfort.
[gentle music continues]
[soft chuckle]
Yeah.
[dramatic exhalation]
I thought you were leaving.
I didn't want you to be alone.
- I'm not a monster.
- [gentle music continues]
[tense music]
[Ackerson] I'll let
you two get reacquainted.
[tense music continues]
[steady, metallic pounding]
You are making it very
difficult for me to help you.
- Boss, we're exiting slip space.
- I heard you.
I let them have their way...
[dramatic chuckle]
...you'd already be dead.
We were good to you, Antares.
Oh. Well.
Thank you for
allowing me to barely exist
and to scrape out a meager
living split four ways
with these bozos while you
and your husband spent
- all that Madrigal money on--
- What are you talking about?
Don't play stupid!
I know you're not.
I can usually reason
with my husband,
but when he finds
out about this--
I'm not really worried.
Last I see Soren,
his was on a prison
ship headed for Reach.
So settle in.
It could be a while.
- You're a son of a bitch.
- No, I'm an opportunist.
[distant metallic clanking]
Now, where is it?
[distant clanking continues]
Would somebody please
deal with that?
I can't hear myself think.
[distant clanking continues]
Thank you.
I don't know what
Ruby Ann promised you,
but you are getting played,
Antares, and it's not too late.
Stop, please.
Soren tells you everything.
You know where he's stashed it.
- Stashed what?
- The treasure.
[Laera laughing]
You think this is funny?
Because I guarantee you...
[tense music]
...it's not.
What you call a treasure
was a box full
of deuterium tokens that wasn't
worth much to begin with.
- Heard enough.
- [tense music continues]
Ruby Ann doesn't want the money.
She wants The Rubble.
- [gun cocks]
- [Laera gasps]
- Calm down.
- [tense music continues]
Why are you making me do this?
You think I want to
leave Kessler an orphan?
I love that kid.
She's laughing at you.
[distant clanking continues]
- You hear that sound?
- Yeah.
Yeah, you think you should
do something about it?
I'm watching.
[distant clanking continues]
Go see what's making that sound.
- Where's the stash?
- She's stalling.
Would you shut up?
I don't remember asking
anyone's opinion.
I'm the captain.
This is my ship,
and this is your
last chance, Laera.
[distant
clanking continues]
- Where is it?
- [tense music continues]
I can't tell you
because it doesn't exist.
And if it did exist,
I wouldn't tell you.
[tense music continues]
You've just taken
it outta my hands.
Just remember, I didn't
want what happens next.
[tense music continues]
- [dramatic music]
- [Laera groaning]
- [door beeping]
- [hydraulics hissing]
[tense music]
You have one minute
to rethink your position.
- [countdown beeping]
- [air hissing]
It doesn't have to be this way.
[Laera struggles to breathe]
Think of Kessler!
With Soren on Reach,
who's gonna look after him?
- [Laera struggles to breathe]
- [tense music building]
- Just tell me what I wanna kn--
- [blood splattering]
[alarm blaring]
[sharp gasp]
[gentle music]
- [knife clinking on metal]
- [gentle music continues]
Where's Kessler?
- Kwan?
- [gentle music continues]
Kwan, I asked you a question--
- [Carina grunting]
- [Kwan yelling]
- [knife squelching]
- [tense music continues]
- [Kwan grunting]
- [body thudding]
[gentle music]
- I put him on the transport.
- I told you to stay with him.
- I couldn't.
- Why not?
'Cause then you'd be dead.
[gentle music continues]
[banging on door]
I need to speak
with Corporal Perez.
- She's not here.
- Where is she?
She's a good girl.
Yes, ma'am.
But I think
the devil follows you.
[gentle music]
What time is it?
- Late.
- Uh-huh.
[gentle music continues]
What am I doing here?
Do you remember
what we talked about?
You asked me to...
To don't let them
take me alive?
Yeah, that's right.
Today's the day?
Today's the day.
Thank God.
Ohh.
[gentle music continues]
There's someone here
to see you, Dad.
[gasping]
[gentle music continues]
Oh, Julia.
Julia.
[door opens loudly]
- [heavy footfalls]
- [Perez praying quietly]
Corporal Perez.
[praying softly in Spanish]
- [door closes]
- [Perez continues praying]
Never been in a church before,
have you?
Mnh-mnh.
People come here for comfort.
For protection.
For answers.
Do they find them?
Sometimes.
Do you?
On Sanctuary,
before the Covenant came, I...
I saw something... in the fog.
You mean the woman?
[labored breathing]
She's real, isn't she?
Yes.
I don't sleep.
I can't get that
sound outta my head.
This is a recording
from Sanctuary.
It's not just interference.
Not just a sound.
There's something underneath.
[recording playing Sangheili]
What is it?
[recording playing
Sangheili continues]
A prayer.
[recording playing
Sangheili continues]
I bring you blessings,
people of Reach.
[recording playing Sangheili]
[voice speaks Sangheili]
[Perez] Know that I've
come without mercy.
[voice speaks Sangheili]
[Perez] Without pity.
[Perez] Know that I am the
instrument of your extinction.
[voice speaks Sangheili]
[Perez] I bring this planet
forth as a burnt offering.
[tense music]
[voice speaks Sangheili]
[Perez] Upon this altar,
I place the head of the Demon.
[voice speaks Sangheili]
[Perez] May his blood mark
the way to the Sacred Ring
and consecrate the Great
Journey of my people.
[voice speaks Sangheili]
[Perez] Know that
I am Var 'Gatanai.
[voice speaks Sangheili]
[Perez] Know that I am...
Death.
[tense music]
They're already here...
aren't they?
[tense music continues]
[massive explosion]
[closing theme plays]
[signature theme plays]